Luis Tena



des.luistena@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/luistena



+58 0412-1872283



https://luistena.vercel.app

Summary

With 7 years of experience in Javascript and Python, I have become a Full Stack Developer with a compressive knowledge of React/Next.js and a stronger passion for Backend and DevOps tasks. I am a creative thinker with a friendly and open-minded coworker attitude.

I have been an employee, an entrepreneur, and I am always going to be a student ready for the next challenge.

You could check my GitHub for more https://github.com/devluist

I also like to challenge myself on https://www.hackerrank.com/dev_luist

Experience



Full Stack Developer

SIM Venezuela

Jun 2018 - Aug 2021 (3 years 3 months)

- DevOps:
- * Site Reliability Engineering for running services, cron jobs, APIs, Databases, and Data integrity itself
- * Prometheus and Grafana dashboard and SQL/PromQL queries for reports, health checks, and monitoring
- * Automation Scripting: development of Bash/Python scripts
- * Servers setup: Nginx, domains, ssh keys, firewall setup, etc
- React.js: co-developer on some of the projects for clients and internal projects of the company
- * DonDemand Admin / Liveri. dashboard for Marketplace web app

Entrepreneur

Self-employed

Dec 2013 - Mar 2015 (1 year 4 months)

My first attempt at entrepreneurship.

This app was a Venezuelan freelancer web app since, by that time, people could not access dollars freely. This app was intended to alleviate the situation.

I learned the technical side:

- Python2.5/Django 1.4 programming
- How to customize a website looks with -by that time- modern CSS3 + Boostrap3 and HTML5
- Deployment to a Server through Heroku services

And also learned the business side:

- Business Canvas and MVP as a proposal to gain users, investment
- Advertising, Marketing, and pitching of ideas
- Networking

I made mistakes, especially on the business side, but I took note of them to avoid them in the future.

Sadly I could not afford to keep the development, and by this time, we Venezuelans saw difficult times economically. So I decided to stop and culminate college as plan B.

Education



🔀 Universidad de Oriente (VE)

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2008 - 2018

Licenses & Certifications

EF SET English Certificate 67/100 (C1 Advanced) - EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

https://www.efset.org/cert/HB4mJK

(A) Intermediate Python - freeCodeCamp

https://freecodecamp.org/certification/dev_luist/scientific-computing-with-pytho

(A) Back End Development and APIs - freeCodeCamp

https://freecodecamp.org/certification/dev_luist/back-end-development-and-apis

Skills

PostgreSQL • React.js • GraphQL • Git • FastAPI • Express.js • MongoDB • Docker • Linux • Python